Henry-Russell Hitchcock
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Chronological Name and Subject Files, 1919-1987, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-22; 21.9 linear ft.)
  - Correspondence, W-Z, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, A, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, B, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Bills Paid, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, C, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, D-E, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, F-H, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, I-J, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, K-L, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Mac/Mc, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Mah-Ma, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, P, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Pugin's Contrasts (Introduction), 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Ra-Rh, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Ro, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Sob, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Soc, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Sou-Sw, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, W, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Y-Z; Unknown and Illegible, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, A, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, B, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Bills Paid, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Brownstone Revival Committee of New York City, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, C, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, D-E, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Europe-Summer, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, F, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, G, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, H, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, In the Nature of Materials (Reprint), 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, J-L, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Maa-Mac/Mc, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Mar-Mas, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Me-Mu, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, N, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, O-Pe, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Ph-R, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Soc, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, St-Su, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, W-Z, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, A, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, B, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Banking, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Bills Paid, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, C, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, G, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Insurance, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, H, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, I-L, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Lotus, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, M, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, N, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, O, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, P, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, R, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, S, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, W, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Y-Z, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, A, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, B, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Banking, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, C, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, D-E, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, F-G, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, H, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, J, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, K-L, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, M, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, P, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, R-S, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, W, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, A, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, B, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, C, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, D, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, E-F, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, G, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, H, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, I-K, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, L, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, M, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, P, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Q-R, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, S, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, State Capitols Research Project, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, W-Z, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, A, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, B, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, C, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, G, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, H, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, J-K, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, L, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, M, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, P, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, R, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, S, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, W, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Yale University, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, A, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, B, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, C, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, D-E, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, F, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, G-H, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, I-K, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, L, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, M, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, P, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, R, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, S, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, W, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Y-Z, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, A, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, B, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, C, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, D, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, E-F, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, G, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, H-I, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, J-K, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, L, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, M, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, P, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, R, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Sm, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Soc, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Society of Architectural Historians of Great Britain - St, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1975, (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, American State Capitol Project-Vo, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, W, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Y-Z, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, A, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, B, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, C, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, G, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, H, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, I, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, L, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, M, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Penguin Books, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, P, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, R, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, S-Smith, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Smithsonian Institution, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Society of Architectural Historians, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Society of Architectural Historians of Great Britain, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1976 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, American State Capitol Project, 1976 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, W-Y, 1976 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1976 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, A, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, B, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, C, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, D-E, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, F, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, G, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, H, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, I-L, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, M, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Na-Newh, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, New York University, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, New York University Seminar, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, No-O, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, P-R, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Sob, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Soc-Sz, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1977, (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, American State Capitols Research Project, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, W, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, V, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Y-Z, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Ab-Architectural Design, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Architectural History Foundation Inc., 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Art-Av, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Ba-Bl, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Bl-Bu, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, C, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, G, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, H, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, J-L, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, M, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Na, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Ne-No, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, O-P, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, R, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Sm, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Society of Architectural Historians, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Architectural Society of Great Britain-St, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, W-Z, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, A, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, B, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, B-C, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Court House, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, G, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, H, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, I-J, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, K-L, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, M, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, P, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, R, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Sob, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Society of Architectural Historians, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Society of Architectural Historians of Great Britain-St, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, T-V, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1979, (3 folders) (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, W-Z, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, A-Am, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Architectural History Foundation Inc., 1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, As-At, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Avery Library Search Committee, Columbia University, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Av-Ay, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, Birthday, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, B, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, C, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, G-H, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, J-K, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, L, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Mac/Mc, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Macmillian Encyclopedia of Architects, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Mar-Mu, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Na-New York State, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, New York University, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, O, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, P-Q, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, R, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, S, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, T, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, V, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, W, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, A-B, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, C-D, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, E-F, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, G, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, H-J, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, K, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, L, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, M, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, P, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, R, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, S, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, T, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Victorian Society in America, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, W-Z, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, A, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Avery Study Center, Columbia University, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, B, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, C-D, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, G, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, H, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, J-L, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, McCormick, Thomas J,, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, M, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, P, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, R, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, T-Z, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, A-Am, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Architectural History Foundation Inc., 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Architectural Review - At, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, B, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, C, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, G, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, H-L, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, M, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, P-R, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, S, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, T-U, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, V-Z, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1983 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Ab-Ad, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Architectural History Foundation Inc., 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, As-Au, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, B, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, C, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, D, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, G, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, J-L, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, M, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, N-P, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, R-T, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, V-W, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Architectural History Foundation Inc., 1985 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, At-B, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, C, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, F-L, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, M-R, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, S-W; Illegible and Unknown, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, A, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, B-C, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, G, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, K-M, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, N-R, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, S-V, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, W-Y, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1987 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, A-D, undated (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, F-H, undated (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, J-K, undated (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, L-S, undated (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, T-W, undated (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Christmas Cards, undated (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, Illegible and Unknown, undated (Box 22)
- Writings, 1922-circa 1978, Series 3:; (Boxes 23-24; 2.0 linear ft.)
  Writings by Hitchcock consist of manuscripts and drafts of published and unpublished articles, book chapters, and his masters thesis, arranged alphabetically by title. Among the texts and notes for lectures and talks are: "War Influence on Architecture" (broadcast on WYG radio, Syracuse, NY., 1942); "Painting Toward Architecture" (Wadsworth Athenaeum at the exhibition's opening, 1947);"Some Self-conscious Victorians or Victorian Postmodernists: Lamb and Harris" (Apostles Club, Wesleyan University, 1948); "Landscape and Cityscape" (International Design Conference, Aspen, Colorado, 1955); and "Interplay between Foreign and American Stylistic Influences after 1869" (Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1970). Other writings by Hitchcock include book reviews, notes, outlines, photo lists, and a bibliography.
  John Coolidge and Sir Wilfred Green are among the other authors represented in this series.
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  3.1: By Hitchcock, 1922-circa 1978
  3.2: By Other Authors, circa 1927-1948
  - By Hitchcock, 1922-circa 1978, 3.1:
    - Articles, Book Chapters, etc., undated (Box 23)
      - American Architectural Books (Box 23)
      - "American Architecture in Europe," undated (Box 23)
      - "American Architecture in 1937: Recovery and the Sense of Form," 1937 (Box 23)
      - "American Influence Abroad" (in The Rise of An America Architecture, ed. Kaufmann), 1967, undated (Box 23)
      - "The American Scene: Autumn 1950," 1950 (Box 23)
      - "Architectural Graphic Art," undated (Box 23)
      - Architecture: 19th and 20th Centuries (Pelican Art History series, 2nd and 3rd editions), 1967-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
      - "Architecture in the Romantic Scene a Hundred Years Ago," undated (Box 23)
      - "Banded Arches before the Year 1000," undated (Box 23)
      - "Brickwork in Classical Rome," undated (Box 23)
      - "Brunel and Paddington," undated (Box 23)
      - The Buildings We See (with Philip Johnson), undated (Box 23)
      - "Cast Iron Warehouses, Jamaica St., Glasgow, 1955-1956," undated (Box 23)
      - Cima da Conegliano: A Special Study of his Works in American Collections with a Register of General Lists, 1927 (Box 23)
      - "Devey, Webb and Norman Shaw," undated (Box 23)
      - "The Distribution of Brick Architecture in France," undated (Box 23)
      - Early American Architecture (foreword), undated (Box 23)
      - "English Architecture Today," undated (Box 23)
      - Encyclopedia of World Art, undated (Box 23)
      - "Eupalinus or the Architect," undated (Box 23)
      - "Frank Lloyd Wright," undated (Box 23)
      - "Free Cadenzas in the American Greek Revival," undated (Box 23)
      - "Germany: 1955-1965, More Especially Dusseldorf," 1964 (Box 23)
      - "The 'High' Stylistic Movement in Victorian Architecture," undated (Box 23)
      - "A House by the Sea," undated (Box 23)
      - "Housing," undated (Box 23)
      - In the Nature of Materials (foreword to the 1969 edition; bibliographical note, 1942-1968), 1969 (Box 23)
      - "Industrial Architecture," undated (Box 23)
      - "The International Style after Twenty Years," undated (Box 23)
      - "Introduction to a Novel," undated (Box 23)
      - "Is it a New World?" undated (Box 23)
      - Latin American Architecture, 1955 (Box 23)
      - Medieval Brickwork (M.A. thesis), circa 1923, (4 folders) (Box 23)
      - Modern Architecture, undated, (9 folders) (Box 23)
      - "New York is Not America," undated (Box 23)
      - "Notes of a Traveler" (parts 1 and 2), undated (Box 23)
      - Painting Toward Architecture (preface to the new edition), 1968 (Box 23)
      - "Paris: 1937," undated (Box 23)
      - "Preservation and Reconstruction," undated (Box 23)
      - "Review of Foreign Periodicals," undated (Box 23)
      - "Review of Reviews," undated (Box 23)
      - Rhode Island Architecture (Chapter IV, "Early Industrial Architecture, 1790-1880"), undated (Box 23)
      - Rococo Architecture in Southern Germany (preface and glossary), 1968 (Box 24)
      - Romantic Gardens, undated (Box 24)
      - "Sandcastles," undated (Box 24)
      - "Six Modern European Houses," undated (Box 24)
      - SOM: The Architecture of Skidmore, Owings and Merrill, 1950- 1962 (introduction), 1961 (Box 24)
      - "Some American Interiors in the Modern Style," undated (Box 24)
      - "Sonato Olympos," undated (Box 24)
      - "Springfield Architecture: 1800-1900," 1934 (Box 24)
      - "The Study of Architecture in the Liberal Arts College," undated (Box 24)
      - "Towards a New Order," undated (Box 24)
      - "Two Books that Exist and Two that do Not," undated (Box 24)
      - "Venetian Painting," undated (Box 24)
      - Victorian Architecture in Britain, undated, (8 folders) (Box 24)
      - "The Wall," undated (Box 24)
      - "West Coast Architecture as Seen by an Easterner," undated (Box 24)
      - Untitled Articles by Hitchcock, undated (Box 24)
    - Bibliography of Writings by Henry-Russell Hitchcock, circa 1978 (Box 24)
    - Book Reviews, circa 1927-1948, undated (Box 24)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1922 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1941 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1942 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1947 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1948 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1950 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1952 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1953 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1954 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1955 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1956 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1957 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1959 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1960 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1965 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1967 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1968 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1970 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1974 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1975 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1976 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, 1977 (Box 24)
    - Lectures, undated (Box 24)
    - Notes, Outlines, Photo Lists, etc., 1958-1954, undated (Box 24)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 24)
  - By Other Authors, circa 1927-1948, 3.2:
    - Writings by Colleagues, circa 1927-1948 (Box 24)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1928-1977, Series 4:; (Box 25; 0.1 linear ft.)
  Architectural drawings are by Hitchcock and others, with some of the unidentified drawings possibly by Hitchcock. Financial records consist mainly of receipts and invoices. Additional financial records appear in Series 1: Alphabetical Files in folders for various years entitled Correspondence, Banking, Correspondence, Bills Paid, and Correspondence, Income Tax.
  - Alien Registration Card (British) of Peter van der Meulen Smith, 1928 (Box 25 (hol))
  - Architectural Drawings probably by Hitchcock, undated (Box 25 (hol))
  - Book Contracts, 1928-1977 (Box 25 (hol))
  - Financial Records, 1928-1961, undated (Box 25 (hol))
- Printed Material, 1922-1984, Series 5:; (Box 25; 0.4 linear ft.)
  The majority of printed material consists of articles about, by, or mentioning Henry-Russell Hitchcock. Also included are advertisements for his books, and postcards (mainly blank) of architectural subjects. Clippings about miscellaneous subjects include articles about historic preservation, architects, and colleagues.
  - Advertisements for Books by Hitchcock, 1954-1982, undated (Box 25 (hol))
  - Article by Hitchcock, "Romantic Gardens, 1750-1850: The Rise, Spread, and Decline of Naturalistic Gardening with a Theory of Modern Gardening," 1932 (Box 25 (hol))
  - Clippings (Box 25 (hol))
    - About Hitchcock, 1929-1984, undated (Box 25 (hol))
    - Reviews of Books by Hitchcock (A-Z by title), 1930-1980 (Box 25 (hol))
    - Reviews of Books by Others, 1967-1982 (Box 25 (hol))
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1941-1986 (Box 25 (hol))
  - Invitations, undated (Box 25 (hol))
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 26 (hol))
    - About Architecture, 1955-1960, undated (Box 26 (hol))
    - Other Subjects, 1922-1974, undated (Box 26 (hol))
  - Postcards, undated (Box 26 (hol))
- Photographs, circa 1926-1979, Series 6:; (Box 26; 0.3 linear ft.)